Finding Aid for the Anaïs Nin Papers, ca. 1910-1977 LSC.2066
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Diaries by Anaïs Nin, 1914-1965; 12.4 Linear Feet
  - Diaries by Anaïs Nin, 1939-1965; 9.0 lin ft. (106 folders)
    - Diary [108]. 1964 - all. Mon Journal. Journal des Autres, Looseleaf. pp.[651]-[825]. (Box 35, Folder 7)
      With AN's letters to Hugh Guiler, Gunther Stuhlmann, Joseph Losey, p.[212].
      (folder 5 of 5)
    - Diary [109]. Hugo's letters, etc., 1964.; Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[117]. (Box 36, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Hugh Guiler, Dominique Aubier, Marguerite [Duras], Roger Bloom, Bruce Tsuchida and others.
      With poems by Daisy Aldan and program for a concert by Joaquin Nin-Culmell.
      With promotional material re the ondioline (an electronic musical instrument).
    - Diary [110]. 1965 - all., January-March 1965.; Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[147]. (Box 36, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Alan Swallow, Deena Metzger, Hugh Guiler, Roger Bloom, Josseph Losey, Joaquin Nin-Culmell, Gunther Stuhlmann, Nobuko Uenishi, Daisy Aldan.
      With letters from Henry Barzun, Hugo Raes, Andre Bay, Henry Miller (photocopies), Robert Baldock and others.
      With copies of AN's letters to Alan Swallow, Hugh Guiler, "Dear Cousin" [Eduardo Sanchez], Roger Bloom, Gunther Stuhlmann and others.
      With Joaquin Nin-Culmell's corrections and questions re AN's diary manuscript, pp.[82]-[86].
    - Diary [110]. 1965 - all., January-March 1965.; Looseleaf. pp.[148]-[322]. (Box 36, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Alan Swallow, Deena [Metzger], Hugh Guiler, Eduardo [Sanchez], Henry Miller (photocopies), Jean Varda, Marguerite Duras, Daisy Alan, Joaquin Nin-Culmell, Oliver Evans.
      With letters from Renate Druks, Andre Bay, Peter Gwen, Gunther Stuhlmann, Thorvald Nin, Inge Bogner, Nobuko Uenishi, Harriet Zinnes, H.M. Barzun, Marguerite [Young?] and others.
      With AN's letters to Hugh Guiler, Inge Bogner and others.
    - Diary [110]. 1965 - all., January-March 1965.; Looseleaf. pp.[323]-[467]. (Box 36, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Alan Swallow, Deena Metzger, Hugh Guiler, Robert Haas, Jerzy Kosinski, p.[434], Don Bachardy, p.[430], Rebecca West, p.[463], Jean Varda.
      With letters from Dominique Aubier, Gunther Stuhlmann, Henry Miller (photocopies), Joaquin Nin-Culmell, Nona Balakian, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Daisy Aldan, Marguerite Young and others.
      With copies of AN's letters to Henry Miller, Hugh Guiler, Daisy Aldan and others.
    - Diary [110]. 1965 - all., January-March 1965.; Numbered p.[468]. (Box 36, Folder 5)
      This folder contains "Story of Diary Editing & Publishing" by AN, written in a Japanese fan foldbook, September 1965.
    - Diary [110]. 1965 - all., January-March 1965.; pp.[469]-[652]. Looseleaf. (Box 36, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from Alan Swallow, Deena Metzger, Hugh Guiler, Roger Bloom, Oliver Evans, Rebecca West, Robert Kirsch, Eve Miller, Rupert Pole, "Annette," James Spicer, Edmund Wilson.
      With letters from Helen & Lloyd Wright, pp.[586]-[588], Peter Gwen, Daisy Aldan, Joaquin Nin-Culmell, Gunther Stuhlmann and others.
      With copies of AN's letters to Rupert Pole, Adelle Davis, Alan Swallow, Wilbur Jordan Smith, Oliver Evans, Gunther Stuhlmann and others.
    - Diary [111]. Hugo letters, etc., 1965.; Looseleaf. pp.[1]-[118]. (Box 37, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from Hugh Guiler, Jerry Bick, Joyce Aaron, Lawrence & Claude Durrell, Roger Bloom, Anne Metzger and others.
      With datebook pages interspersed.
      With theatre programs and ephemera and a clipping re Frances Steloff.
    - Diary [111]. Hugo letters, etc., 1965.; Looseleaf. pp.[119]-[217]. (Box 37, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Hugh Guiler, Roger Bloom, Kathleen Chase, Daisy Aldan, "Marguerite" and others.
    - Diary [111]. 1965. Hugo letters, etc., Looseleaf. pp.[218]-[325]. (Box 37, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Hugh Guiler, Roger Bloom, Lilla van Saher, Bern Porter.
    - Diary [111]. 1965. Hugo letters, etc., Looseleaf. pp.[326]-[[458]. (Box 37, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Hugh Guiler, Renate Druks, Daisy Aldan, Roger Bloom, Lilla van Saher, Nona Balakian, Inge Bogner and others.
      With concert programs.
  - Publication Party, 1980; .10 lin ft. (1 folder)
    Film of reception to mark publication of Diary 7.
    - Film footage of reception held in the Department of Special Collections, UCLA, for the publication of Anaïs Nin's diary, volume 7, July 11, 1980.; 1 reel. 7.5 cm. diameter. 8 mm. film. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Fiction by Anaïs Nin, 1916-1950; .25 linear ft. (4 folders)
  Short stories by Anaïs Nin.
  - Contes I. La maison fermée, Suivis de l'aveugle, Tragedie, 1916.; Holograph. Bound in dark blue/charcoal/silver/gold marbled paper with dark blue half leather binding. 200 leaves. 18 × 21 cm. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    [New York], Biblioteque Bleu "Pour Tous."
  - Contes II. Trois petits diables, [1916].; Holograph. Bound in dark blue/charcoal/silver/gold marbled paper with dark blue half leather binding. 221 leaves, 17.5 × 21.2 cm. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    [New York], Biblioteque Bleu "Pour Tous,"
  - The gypsy feeling! Louveciennes, France, ca. 1931.; Typescript(carbon). In a black folder decorated with original surrealist designs, probably by Miss Anaïs Nin. 6 leaves. 27 cm. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    A short story. Publishing history unknown.
    Original cataloging text for this item by Brooke Whiting, April 1977.
  - Auletris. Carmel: [Press of the Sunken Eye], 1950.; Typescript. 51pp. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Contents:
    Book I, "Life in Provincetown," pp.1047.
    Book II, "Marcel," pp.1-51.
    See also boxes 7 & 8 for erotica by AN.
- Lectures, Interviews, Public Appearances by Anaïs Nin, 1962-1973 and n.d.; 8 oversize boxes.
  This series includes Anaïs Nin speaking on various topics, including psychoanalysis, discussion of her novels and the craft of writing, interviews promoting her books and feminism.
  - Cassette Tapes, 1962-1972; 4 oversize boxes (81 cassette tapes)
    Lectures, interviews, public appearances by Anaïs Nin.
    - Anaïs Nin at College of Marin, October 1972.; Tape no.21 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Side 1 - Philadelphia College of Art doctorate and Marin College, Side 2 - conclusion Marin College, 1972 October 13 and 1973 June 1.; Tape no.22 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Side 1 - Marin College, 1973.; Tape no.23 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Side 1 - "On writing," Marin College and Side 2 - "On writing." Marin College, February 8, 1973.; Tape no.24 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Side 1 - Part II of "On writing," Marin College, February 8, 1973.; Tape no.25 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Side 1 - Talk for Second Wave, feminist magazine, Boston (Summer 1971) and Side 2 - on "Craft of writing," Marin College, Summer 1971 and February 8, 1973.; Tape no.26 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Side 1 - "On writing," Marin College (no.3), February 8, 1973.; Tape no.27; 10 minutes. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Side 1 - Cal Tech lecture and Side 2 - Cal Tech lecture, continued, February 13, 1973.; Tape no.28 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Side 1 - Cal Tech lecture (conclusion), February 13, 1973.; Tape no.29 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Side 1 & 2 - Santa Clara, February 1973.; Tape no.30 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Side 2 (only) - Beginning talk. Santa Clara, February 10, 1973.; Tape no.31 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Side 1 - completion of talk at Santa Clara, February 10, 1973.; Tape no.32 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Side 1 - Sale, Proskauer, Part III and Side 2 - Sale, Proskauer, Part IV, [October 6-8, 1972].; Tape no.33 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Side 1 - Sale, Proskauer, Part I and Side 2 - Sale, Proskauer, Part II, October 6-8, 1972.; Tape no.34 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Side 1 - "Sale, The Dream," talk with Dr. Proskauer and Side 2 - "Sale, The Dream," Talk with Dr. Proskauer, October 6-8, 1972.; Tape no.35 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Sale, The Dream," completion of talk with Dr. Proskauer, October 6-8, 1972.; Tape no.36; 15 minutes. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - The emerging woman, March 21, 1973.; Tape no.37 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Also noted as tape no.101-0742.
    - Side 1 - "Book Beat," Chicago, Cromie, 1972.; Tape no.38; 30 minutes. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Side 1 - "Book Beat," Chicago and Side 2 - "Book Beat," Chicago, 1972.; Tape no.39 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Side 1 - Anaïs Nin visit to Dartmouth and Side 2 - Talk at Dartmouth, November 1972.; Tape no.40 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Denver University lecture, September 28, 1973.; Tape no.41; Sides 1 & 2. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Anaïs Nin lecture. Women's Clinic, 1972.; Tape no.42; Copy. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Anaïs Nin. Lewis and Clark College, Portland, Oregon, April 12, 1972.; Tape no.43; Sides 1 and 2. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Albuquerque, February 15, 1973.; Tape no.44; Sides 1 and 2. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Anaïs Nin, "Adventurous women." Santa Cruz, April 7, 1973.; Tape no.45; Sides 1 and 2. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, February 27, 1973.; Tape no.46; Side 1. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Lewis and Clark College, April 13, 1972.; Tape no.47; Sides 1 and 2. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Womanspace, January 31, 1973.; Tape no.48; Sides 1 and 2. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Skidmore Surrey House discussio, October 30, 1972.; Tape no.49; Side 1. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Side 1, part I - Festival of the Arts, Berkeley (December 2, 1972), part II, Artist magician, Sonoma [College], (April 28, 1973) and Side 2 - completion of Sonoma, December 2, 1972, and April 28, 1973.; Tape no.50 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Sonoma College, April 28, 1973.; Tape no.51; Side 1. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Anaïs Nin seminar. Sonoma, Part I, April 28, 1973.; Tape no.52; Side B only. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Anaïs Nin seminar. Sonoma, Part II, April 29, 1973.; Tape no.53; Side A. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - [Lecture], n.d.; Tape no.1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Unidentified. Includes discussion of the novel of the future and AN reading from diary 3.
    - McGill's Imoversotu. Montreal, Canada, March 7, 1973.; Tape no.2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Speculation, No.238, A conversation with Anaïs Nin [and] Keith Berwick, historian. Channel 28, Tape no.3 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Psychology clinic. Berkeley, California, February 11, 1972.; Tape no.4 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - On women's liberation. Harvard, Memorial Church, May 28, 1971.; Tape no.5 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Anaïs Nin interview (tape 1 of 2), n.d.; Tape no.6; Both sides. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Anaïs Nin interview (tape 2 of 2), n.d.; Tape no.7 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Anaïs Nin and Oliver Evans interview re House of Incest - part 1, Tape no.8a; Sides A & B. 45 minutes. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Anaïs Nin and Oliver Evans interview re House of Incest - part 2, Tape no.8b; 40 minutes. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Sale seminar II - Anaïs Nin, February 12, 1972 (p.m.).; Tape no.9a; 2 hours, unedited. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Sale seminar I, ICC Convention, February 12, 1972 (a.m.).; Tape 9BII (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Sale seminar I, ICC Convention, February 12, 1972 (a.m.).; Tape 9BIII (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Interview for Sweden on Diary, November 1966.; Tape no.10; Copy. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Reed College grad[uation], May 23, 1971.; Tape no.11; Copy. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Anaïs Nin recorded at Northwestern University. "Women and Writing", January 1972.; Tape no.12; 50 minutes. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - "An Evening with Anaïs Nin" - conversation with Judy Chicago, February 14, 1972.; Tape no.14; 1 hour. (Box 12, Folder 16)
      AN discusses her life, work, struggles, feminism and the art world.
      Part II of II.
    - Anaïs Nin with Sally Davis - part I of I, n.d.; Tape no.16; 25 minutes. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Sale lecture - Anaïs Nin, February 11, 1972.; Tape no.17; 2 hours. Unedited. Sides A & B. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Dream symposium. Berkeley Extension, John Pearson, January 18, 1969.; Tape no.18 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Anaïs Nin in conversation with Studs Terkel. WFMT Studios, January 1972.; Tape no.19; 48 minutes. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Anaïs Nin and Oliver Evans re Winter of Artifice, Tape no.20 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Skidmore discussion, October 30, 1972.; Tape no.39 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - College of Marin, October 13, 1972.; Tape no.40 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Anaïs Nin. Furrawn, Berkeley, October 21, 1972.; Tape no.42 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - KPFK Radio. talk in French with Georges Cleyet, n.d.; Tape no.43 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "The New Woman," Ramparts Magazine. Palace of Fine Arts, San Francisco, June 20, 1974.; Tape no.44 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - "Anaïs Nin as Seen Through Her Diary." Tagliaferri, Colorado Radio KCFR, 1974.; Tape no.45 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Talk on Artaud. Middletown University, November 10, 1966.; Tape no.46 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - New Jersey State College talk. Sharon Spencer, 1971.; Tape no.47 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Anaïs Nin reads "Under a Glass Bell" and "Ladders to Fire." American Playwright Theatre, Tape no.48 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Anaïs Nin lecture. Northwestern Illinois University, July 28, 1972.; Tape no.49 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - "Je suis le plus malade des surreal." WABI, New York, April 22, 1964.; Tape no.50 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Anaïs Nin talk. Liberal and Fine Arts Committee, Los Angeles State [College], Tape no.51 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - "Women and Writing." Northwestern University, WFMT, January 1972.; Tape no.52 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Studs Terkel with Anaïs Nin. Northwestern University, WFMT, January 1972.; Tape no.53 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Anaïs Nin and Rupert Pole. KPFK radio, Michaux Babel, July 13, 1962.; Tape no.54 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Tree College talk, 1966.; Tape no.55 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Anaïs Nin reads from Diary 4. KPFK, February 14, 1972.; Tape no.56 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Womanspace, n.d.; Tape no.57 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.58A (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.58B (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.59A (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.59B, part II (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.60; Side A. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      >Note: Tapes 60-72 are with Marguerite Young alone and with Anaïs Nin.
    - Marguerite Young, November 15, 1964.; Tape no.61; Side A. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Marguerite Young, September 6, 1964.; Tape no.62; Side A. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.63 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.64; Sides A & B. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Marguerite [Young] & Brodin, n.d.; Tape no.65; Sides A & B. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.66; Sides A & B. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.67; Side A. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Marguerite Young alone and with Anaïs Nin, Tape no.68 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Marguerite Young, December 1964.; Tape no.69; Side A. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Marguerite Young, 1964.; Tape no.70; Sides A & B. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Marguerite Young, December 1964.; Tape no.71; Side A. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Marguerite Young, December 1964.; Tape no.72; Sides A & B. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - University of Colorado, Denver, Talk I, September 28, 1973.; Tape no.73; Sides A & B. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - University of Colorado, Denver. Talk II, September 28, 1973.; Tape no.73(2); Side A. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Conversation on malingering and anxiety, Tape no.81; Side A. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes, n.d.; 0.1 Linear Feet (4 inch tapes)
    Taped conversation with Anaïs Nin.
    - Conversation on malingering and anxiety, Tape no.81 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes, 1964-1973 and n.d.; (5 inch reels) 2 oversize boxes (25 tapes)
    - On women's liberation. Harvard, Memorial Church, May 28, 1971.; Tape no.5 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Anaïs Nin interview (tape 1 of 2), n.d.; Tape no.6; Both sides. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Anaïs Nin interview, (tape 2 of 2), n.d.; Tape no.7 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Anaïs Nin talk with Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no. 60 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Tapes 60 - 72 are tapes of Marguerite Young alone and with Ian Hugo (Hugh Guiler) and Anaïs Nin.
    - Marguerite Young, November 15, 1964.; Tape no.61 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Hugo & Marguerite Young on diary, Chico illness.
    - Marguerite Young, September 6, 1964.; Tape no.62 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Publication of book, Scribner's reaction, new publisher, Jane Gwen.
    - Marguerite Young and Anaïs Nin, Tape no.63 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Marguerite Young fixes her apartment, goes to Joyce's meeting, meets his sister, Leon Edel, on poetry.
    - Anaïs Nin and Marguerite Young, Tape no.64 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Guggenheim, 7 boxes, a horse and carriage, reads clam digger, Mr. Spitzer.
    - Marguerite Young and Brodin, Tape no.65 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      E. Hardwick, Capote, Lowell, McCarthy, Ruth Stephan, Joaquin, Jesuits - Gonzalo, Brodin on Swados, Powers, Malamud on Brodin, best sellers omitted.
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.66 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Dreiser, Ginsberg, America, Indiana, Mari Sandoz, Ruth Stephan, Elizabeth Bowen, Gene Bars, Claude Fredericks, Sylvia & Ted Kennedy, Burroughs, Mitchell, end of book, Maxwell Perkins.
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.67 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Troubles with her book, wants publicity agent, comments on diary, teaching.
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.68 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      On fame, reputation, Nona, Marshall, Spain - Pride, W.C. Williams - on woman [sic], New York Times.
    - Marguerite Young, December 1964.; Tape no.69 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Howard Moss, Norman Zierald, party - [illegible], Ellison, Ahmed, Bob [illegible], Seehair, [illegible].
    - Marguerite Young, March 1964.; Tape no.70 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Feldman, Guggenheim, problems of teaching - science fiction, T.V., John Stephan Reilly.
    - Marguerite Young, December 1964.; Tape no.71 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Marguerite Marshall-Gwen story - description of Gwen wedding, Mary McCarthy, comments on birth in diary, Zierald, No[h] plays ... Nobuko.
    - Marguerite Young, December 1964.; Tape no.72 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Esther Longtree reading, discussion with H[?].
    - University of Colorado, Denver, September 28, 1973.; Tape no.73[a]; Sides 1 & 2. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - University of Colorado, Denver, September 28, 1973.; Tape no.73[b]; Side 1 only. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - "An Evening with Anaïs Nin." College of Marin, October 13, 1972.; Tape no.74; 1 hour. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Anaïs Nin and Tom Robbins. Festival of the Arts, UC Berkeley, December 2, 1972.; Tape no.75 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Second Wave. Boston, Summer 1971.; Tape no.76 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Anaïs Nin talk, June 1, 1973.; Tape no.77 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - "The Craft of Writing." College of Marin, February 8, 1973.; Tape no.78 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Nin, Lyon & Proskauer, "The Dream," Sale, October 6-8, 1972.; Tape no.79 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      Tape 1 of 2.
    - Nin, Lyon & Proskauer, "The Dream," Sale, October 6-8, 1972.; Tape no.80 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      Tape 2 of 2.
  - Reel-to-Reel Tapes, 1964-1973 and n.d.; (7 inch reels) 2 oversize boxes (39 tapes)
    - [lecture], n.d.; Tape no.1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Unidentified. Includes discussion of the novel of the future and Anaïs Nin reading from diary 3.
    - McGill's Imoversotu. Montreal, Canada, March 7, 1973.; Tape no.2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Speculation, no.238, A conversation with Anaïs Nin [and] Keith Berwick, historian. Channel 28, Tape no.3 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Psychology clinic. Berkeley, California, February 11, 1972.; Tape no.4 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Anaïs Nin and Oliver Evans interview re House of Incest - part 1, Tape no.8a; 45 minutes. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Anaïs Nin and Oliver Evans interview re House of Incest - part 2, Tape no.8b; 40 minutes. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Sale seminar II - Anaïs Nin (p.m.), February 12, 1972.; Tape no.9a; 2 hours, unedited. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Sale seminar I, ICC convention (a.m.), February 12, 1972.; Tape no.9b (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Interview for Sweden on Diary, November 1966.; Tape no.10; Copy. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Reed College grad[uation], May 23, 1971.; Tape no.11; Copy. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Anaïs Nin recorded at Northwestern University, [on] Women and writing, January 1972.; Tape no.12; 50 minutes. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Talk at Marin College, October 13, 1972.; Tape no.13 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Anaïs Nin and Judy Chicago, February 14, 1972.; Tape no.15 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      (duplicate tape)
    - An evening with Anaïs Nin - conversation with Judy Chicago, February 14, 1972.; Tape no.14; 1 hour. (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Nin discusses her life, work, struggles, feminism and the art world.
    - Anaïs Nin with Sally Davis - part I of I, n.d.; Tape no.16; 25 minutes. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Sale lecture - Anaïs Nin, February 1972.; Tape no.17; 2 hours, unedited. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Dream symposium. Berkeley Extension, John Pearson, January 18, 1969.; Tape no.18 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Anaïs Nin in conversation with Studs Terkel. WFMT Studios, January 1972.; Tape no.19; 58 minutes. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Anaïs Nin and Oliver Evans re Winter of Artifice, Tape no.20 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Skidmore discussion, October 30, 1972.; Tape no.39 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - College of Marin, October 3, 1972.; Tape no.40 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Anaïs Nin furrawn. Berkeley, October 21, 1972.; Tape no.42 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Talk in French with Georges Cleyet. KPFK Radio, n.d.; Tape no.43 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "The New Woman," Ramparts Magazine. Palace of Fine Arts, San Francisco, June 20, 1974.; Tape no.44 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "Anaïs Nin as Seen Through Her Diary." Tagliaferri, Colorado radio, KCFR, 1974.; Tape no.45 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Talk on Artaud. Middletown University, November 10, 1966.; Tape no.46 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - New Jersey State College talk. Sharon Spencer, 1971.; Tape no.47 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Anaïs Nin reads Under a Glass Bell and Ladders to Fire. American Playwright Theatre, Tape no.48 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Anaïs Nin lecture. Northwestern Illinois University, July 28, 1972.; Tape no.49 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Je suis le plus malade des surreal." WABI, New York, April 22, 1964.; Tape no.50 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Anaïs Nin talk. Liberal and Fine Arts Committee, Los Angeles State [College], Tape no.51 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Women and Writing." Northwestern University, WFMT, January 1972.; Tape no.52 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Studs Terkel with Anaïs Nin. Northwestern University, WFMT, January 1972.; Tape no.53 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Anaïs Nin and Rupert Pole. KPFK radio, Michaux Babel, July 13, 1962.; Tape no.54 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Tree College talk, 1966.; Tape no.55 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Anaïs Nin reads from Diary 4. KPFK, February 14, 1972.; Tape no.56 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Womanspace, n.d.; Tape no.57 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.58 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Marguerite Young, n.d.; Tape no.59 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Material about Anaïs Nin, 1983-1984; .20 linear ft. (2 folders)
  Articles re Anaïs Nin.
  - Kraft, Barbara, "Historic houses: Anaïs Nin's house of light." Architectural Digest, January 1984.; pp.100-107. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Anaïs: an International Journal. Los Angeles, California, 1983-1984. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    vol.1, 1983.
    vol.2, 1984.
- Memorabilia re Anaïs Nin, n.d.; 0.2 Linear Feet
  T-shirt.
  - Cotton t-shirt with likeness of Anaïs Nin and her name printed in brown on the front (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Memorial Service, February 22, 1977; .10 linear ft. (1 cassette)
  Tribute.
  - Anaïs Nin tribute. Los Angeles, February 22, 1977.; 1 audio cassette. (Box 7, Folder 2)